Philippine Rubat du Mérac

(415) 949 9283 - philippine.merac@gmail.com - Los Angeles

PROFILE

9+ years' experience in marketing and communications in the Art, Services, and Industrial sectors. I am naturally pro-active, a multitasker with an appetite to learn. My passion for Art is matched by rigorous organizational skills and a sharp eye for detail. Raised in France, I hold a current U.S. Green Card.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Feb 2016 – Aug 2017 (1 year 6 months) Registrar & Communication at the Niki Charitable Art Foundation – San Diego, USA

Reported to NCAF Archives Director & Trustees

Maintenance of the art collection & promotion of the artist's heritage

- Collection Maintenance (1,000 sculptures and 5,000 graphic works of art): artwork handling, condition reports, inventory, preservation, packing
- Transport Organization: worked as a key contact for the Foundation for sending and receipt of artworks, coordination between shipping companies and recipients, pro forma invoices
- · Communication: directed social media, wrote monthly newsletter, composed blogs and updates on nikidesaintphalle.org
- Image Processing: cleaned and color corrected archival pictures and artwork images for publication (online and offline)
- Market Monitoring: tracked market alerts, screened for counterfeit sales, published past auction results, built relationships with small & medium European auction houses

Aug 2015 – Present (2 years 5 months)

Artist Manager for KASHINK, French Street Artist – Paris, FRANCE

- Facilitated residency in Los Angeles (October 2018) and a performance in Paris (January 2018)
- Facilitated artist's residencies at PowWow Long Beach and at the Container Yard (DTLA), July 2016
- Scouted locations in San Diego, which resulted in 5 new pieces in-situ in Barrio Logan, July 2016
- Organized first Paris solo show of artist December 2015 : Paris, Chéri-e
 - Media coverage: wrote press release and articles, managed invitations, organized press conference at opening, attended networking and media events with KASHINK, collected press reviews
 - Sponsorship: Sourced opportunities with NATURALIA and POSCA, negotiated commercial partnership with ART.COM to integrate KASHINK portfolio on their site and feature a dozen framed artworks during *Paris*, *Chéri-e*
 - Online & Offline communication: Created & maintained the parischeriexpo.com website and social media campaigns
 - Sales: organized private collector tour of *Paris*, *Chéri-e* and sold two important pieces, served as customer liaison to price and explain pieces (technique, story, and artistic intention) and insure delivery of authenticity certificates
- Launched KASHINK's first book: managed budget, design specs, proofing, marketing, crowd funding, and media coverage

Jun 2012 - Jul 2015 (3 years 2 months) Project Manager at Bianca Medica Agency & BFM Business, Paris, FRANCE

Reported to Bianca Medica Director

Organization of events for international pharmaceutical companies

- Managed events for pharmaceutical companies (seminars, workshops, trainings, debates), including planning, invitations, marketing, event deliverables, and collaboration with partners and providers
- Oversaw participants and event staff to ensure flawless onsite delivery and execution
- Supervised/maintained overall event budgets, including detailed post-event reports to clients, analyzed event ROI
- Identified new opportunities with customers such as AstraZeneca, Bouchara Recordati, Boehringer Ingelheim, SNITEM
- Booked, managed, and marketed weekly international radio broadcast, "Check Up Santé," for BFM Business Radio (96.4)

Nov 2010 – Jan 2012 (1 year 3 months) Marketing & Communication Coordinator at Orange Business Services, Washington DC Reported to Verticals Director

Explain & deliver OBS marketing best practices for all industries

- Developed, implemented, and monitored internal & external communication plans for industrial markets
- Consolidated market analyses regarding potential clients
- Created and maintained "industrial solutions" internal portal and pages (Transport, Bank, Energy) for OBS.com
- Wrote monthly internal & external communications to valorize the OBS expertise
- Launched and managed the "OBS shipping" community on social media (LinkedIn)
- Organized training for sales teams

Jun 2009 – Aug 2010 (1 year 2 months)

Corporate Communication Coordinator - Alcan Packaging HQ, FRANCE

Reported to Communication VP

Enforce CEO communication through different channels for different audiences

- · Created and maintained content for the Alcan Packaging (AP) Corporate intranet and internet sites
- Worked with Vice-President to publish announcements regarding the Amcor and Bemis divestment process, then translated English to French
- Coordinated internal and external communication actions (IT link during the divestment process)
- Organized internal & external events

Mar 2008 - Mar 2009

Internal Communication Coordinator - Air France, NYC, USA

(1 year)

Report to Communication Director

Dynamise the internal communication for AF staff across the USA

- Managed the HR intranet web site "HR4You"
- Content creation for the bi-annual quality magazine and monthly internal reports
- Created "green" projects survey (paper waste reduction, transport subsidies study) and training manual
- Graphic design for Delta Joint Venture posters

COMMUNITY LIFE

2014 - Present

Grand Palais RMN Ambassador

Social media promotions of museum events, with special preview access to press viewings, conferences, and exhibitions

2009 - Present

So Cute So Culture Founder & Manager

- Created after-work cultural event series, "So Cute So Culture," to curate social outings for professionals
- Organized events at museums, galleries, theaters, restaurants, and designed corresponding programs and invitations
- Created visual brand identity across web and social media platforms

2015

CitizenMag Cultural Contributor

Selected to curate Paris art venues, exhibitions and happenings for CitizenMag hotel clients and social followers (60K monthly views) Example: https://www.citizenm.com/citizenmag/paris/places/street-art-under-a-museum

EDUCATION

• 2008 Masters in International Management

PARIS X Nanterre University - Major in Strategy

• 2006 Bachelor in Economic Sciences

PARIS X Nanterre University - Major in Project Management

SKILLS & INTERESTS

ΙT

Google Analytics / Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, InDesign) / Office (Excel, PowerPoint) / Mailchimp / CMS (WordPress, Joomla, SharePoint) / Basic HTML / Artifex Press / ArtBase

Languages

French: native / English: Fluent / Spanish: intermediate

Interests

Reading (Novels, Poetry) / Music (ballets, classical music, operas) / Museums, Galleries, Art Fairs / Traveling (Europe, Turkey, Egypt, Israel, West Africa, China, Cambodia, Vietnam, French Polynesia, USA)